<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Saurav</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Saurav</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Term Paper: Impact of evolving Artificial Intelligence on the Human Race</title><link>/posts/evolving-ai-on-human-race/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/evolving-ai-on-human-race/</guid><description>Impact of evolving Artificial Intelligence on the future of Human Race Saurav Pandey
September 4, 2020 Abstract Link to heading Artificial Intelligence is evolving rapidly and it is bound to impact the way we humans live. This paper attempts to highlight our general perception towards Artificial Intelligence and how it is changing with time. It investigates the history, status quo and future of artificial intelligence and pinpoints its association with human life.</description></item><item><title>Pandas Optimized Code Snippets</title><link>/posts/pandas-optimized-snippets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/pandas-optimized-snippets/</guid><description>Here are the pandas snippets that will make data cleaning easier. These will make the process easier and faster.
#Note: I will gradually update the list
1. To clean numbers and text inside brackets from a column using regex Link to heading import pandas as pd import re df = pd.DataFrame({&amp;#34;Code&amp;#34;:[&amp;#34;EE&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;NP&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;USA&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;ES&amp;#34;],&amp;#34;Country&amp;#34;:[&amp;#34;Estonia{EE}&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Nepal123&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;United States Of America(USA)&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Spain&amp;#34;]}) df df[&amp;#39;Country&amp;#39;] = df[&amp;#39;Country&amp;#39;].replace(r&amp;#34;[\(\[\{].*?[\)\]\}]|[^a-zA-Z ]&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;&amp;#34;,regex=True) df</description></item><item><title>KNN Classifier Implementing from Scratch</title><link>/posts/knn-classifier-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/knn-classifier-from-scratch/</guid><description>KNN is a supervised algorithm that classifies new cases based on similarity measure from its neighbors.
Please refer the notebook below for its detailed implementation and understanding from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Configuring virtualenv and virtualenvwrapper in ubuntu</title><link>/posts/virtualenv-virtualenvwrapper-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/virtualenv-virtualenvwrapper-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>We all must have faced the situation where version of our packages don&amp;rsquo;t match and takes up hours of our time to get solved. A virtual Environment is an isolates working environment of a Python project so that other projects aren&amp;rsquo;t hampered.
So, lets start the configuration with virtualenv. To install it via pip
$ pip install virtualenv See, it is as simple as that. Now, you can work in an isolated python3.</description></item><item><title>Unfolding blockchain’s social aspects</title><link>/posts/unfolding-blockchains-social-aspects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/unfolding-blockchains-social-aspects/</guid><description>With Facebook’s Libra, the crypto-community around the globe has yet more things to talk about, if not be hopeful. The crypto-currencies as well as its underlying blockchain technology together is slowly yet steadily penetrating human life, at least in terms of things to keep an eye on. The same way e-commerce websites were making buzz in the 90’s. If you don’t know already, blockchain is just an open, distributed ledger that hosts growing list of records linked together in such a way that they are append-only and can’t be modified or tampered with.</description></item></channel></rss>